<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>linkstitcher/saveds</title>
        <link>https://github.com/rybla/linkstitcher</link>
        <description>The linkstitcher feed for saved URLs.</description>
        <image>
            <url>https://www.rybl.net/favicon.ico</url>
            <title>rybl/linkstitcher</title>
            <link>https://github.com/rybla/linkstitcher</link>
        </image>
        <item>
            <link>https://www.arxiv.org/pdf/2512.09762</link>
            <pubDate>2025-12-22</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Malleable software: Restoring user agency in a world of locked-down apps</title>
            <link>https://www.inkandswitch.com/essay/malleable-software/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[

Motivation
We want to adapt our environments
Environments matter. To do our best work and live our best lives, we need spaces that let us each express our unique potential.
A guitar maker sets up their workshop with their saws, hammers, chisels and files arranged just so. They can also build new tools as needed to achieve the best result—a wooden block as a support, or a pair of pliers sanded down into the right shape.



Over the years, a home cook gradually assembles a combination of knives, cutting boards, and pots and pans, finding the ones that work best for them. They can install hooks]]></description>
            <pubDate>2025-12-22</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>How Journalists Can Turn Speeches, Blog Posts, Books &amp; News Articles Into Illustrative Infographics Using Nano Banana Pro – The GDELT Project</title>
            <link>https://blog.gdeltproject.org/how-journalists-can-turn-speeches-blog-posts-books-news-articles-into-illustrative-infographics-using-nano-banana-pro/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
                                        Much of the conversation about AI and journalism centers on the potential conflicts between the two fields, while the reality is that there is much AI can offer the field of journalism to help journalists cover a world that is moving ever faster and in a distribution landscape that prioritizes visuals ever more. Given all of our success this week transforming a vast range of material into beautiful and easy-to-understand infographics using Nano Banana Pro, we got to thinking how journalists might be able to use these same approaches. Obviously our work]]></description>
            <pubDate>2025-12-22</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>