<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>linkstitcher/saveds</title>
        <link>https://github.com/rybla/linkstitcher</link>
        <description>The linkstitcher feed for saved URLs.</description>
        <image>
            <url>https://www.rybl.net/favicon.ico</url>
            <title>rybl/linkstitcher</title>
            <link>https://github.com/rybla/linkstitcher</link>
        </image>
        <item>
            <title>Teaching an LLM a Niche Diagraming Language</title>
            <link>https://www.huy.rocks/everyday/12-01-2025-ai-teaching-an-llm-a-niche-diagraming-language</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Text-to-diagram seems to be an area that has been solved perfectly by LLMs, but only with popular languages like Mermaid or PlantUML. There are many other less popular diagramming languages like D2, Structurizr, or Pintora. I want to see how far I can go teaching an LLM one of these languages, and Pintora◹ seems like a nice option to pick because I know there will not be a lot of LLMs trained with this language. At least, not the small ones.
Project goalSo, I set out the goal for this training project. It will be an LLM that has the ability to work with Pintora diagrams, for the following task]]></description>
            <pubDate>2025-12-05</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title></title>
            <link>https://muratkasimov.art/Ya/Tutorials/Command-line-task-manager-7/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[   /Я language (β)/Tutorials/Command line task manager 7/   Full source code ⋅ Previous chapter ⋅ Next chapter Let's introduce task statuses - they either completed or waiting for completion:   type Status = Unit `S` Unit   In addition we add pattern synonyms to avoid confusion:   pattern TODO e = This e     pattern DONE e = That e   Statuses should be included in a task type declaration:   type Task = Status `P` String   Printing expression is bloating, it's good time to split it on lines and blocks:   > line = is @( Cursor `P` Task )     >> `yio'yio'yoi` TODO `hu` "TODO" `la` DONE `hu` "DONE]]></description>
            <pubDate>2025-12-05</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Effect is Kleisli, etymologically</title>
            <link>https://luthenwald.github.io/blogs/effect-kleisli.html</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
      
      
      It's pretty intriguing that the Effect type in this blog is exactly the traditional Kleisli type in haskell. We'll further show that Monad is the constraint we need to form the valid Effect category. If you are wondering about the meaning of effects in the haskell world, I believe this blog will help gain some understanding.
      
import           Data.Kind ( Type )

import           Prelude   hiding ( Just, Maybe, Monad, Nothing, id, return, (<=<), (=<<), (>=>), (>>=) )


      The Effect Type
      When I was perplexitying about effects in haskell, the result was disapp]]></description>
            <pubDate>2025-12-05</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Google Summer of Code 2025 Wrap-up | The Haskell Programming Language&apos;s blog</title>
            <link>https://blog.haskell.org/gsoc-2025/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
    
      Google Summer of Code 2025 Wrap-up

      
          Aaron Allen  November 24, 2025  [Haskell.org] #Summer of Code  #Announcement  #GSoC 

    


The Haskell.org committee is pleased to present the results of Haskell's
participation in the Google Summer of Code 2025. This marks our 14th time
taking part in GSoC!



Of the four projects alloted to our organization, three were successfully
completed:

Implement Signature Help for Haskell Language Server
Qualified Imports and Alias Resolution in Liquid Haskell
Documenting and Improving CMM


Congratulations to all the contributors and]]></description>
            <pubDate>2025-12-05</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>https://www.stackbuilders.com/insights/hasktorch-libtorch-haskell-bindings-for-deep-learning-using-ffi/</title>
            <link>https://www.stackbuilders.com/insights/hasktorch-libtorch-haskell-bindings-for-deep-learning-using-ffi/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Title: https://www.stackbuilders.com/insights/hasktorch-libtorch-haskell-bindings-for-deep-learning-using-ffi/]]></description>
            <pubDate>2025-12-05</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>What if you don&apos;t need MCP at all?</title>
            <link>https://mariozechner.at/posts/2025-11-02-what-if-you-dont-need-mcp/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[



2025-11-02



One chonky MCP server






My Browser DevTools Use CasesProblems with Common Browser DevTools for Your AgentEmbracing Bash (and Code)The Start ToolThe Navigate ToolThe Evaluate JavaScript ToolThe Screenshot ToolThe BenefitsAdding the Pick ToolAdding the Cookies ToolA Contrived ExampleMaking This Reusable Across AgentsIn Conclusion


After months of agentic coding frenzy, Twitter is still ablaze with discussions about MCP servers. I previously did some very light benchmarking to see if Bash tools or MCP servers are better suited for a specific task. The TL;DR: both can be eff]]></description>
            <pubDate>2025-12-05</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Metascience in Dangerous Times</title>
            <link>https://www.macroscience.org/p/metascience-in-dangerous-times</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Ship in a Storm on a Rocky Coast, by Jan Porcellis (painted around 1618). Source: Wikimedia. As Macroscience relaunches, a fundamental question has been on my mind. Namely, how must metascience adapt to understand the shape of science in the coming years?Since we went on hiatus late last year, the Trump administration has fundamentally reconfigured the government’s involvement in American science and research. The norms that govern the degree to which political authorities intervene in the life of the academy have been reshaped. From cuts to research funding to the reworking of overhead rules,]]></description>
            <pubDate>2025-12-07</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <link>https://github.com/zed-industries/awesome-gpui</link>
            <description><![CDATA[# awesome-gpui

A hybrid immediate and retained mode, GPU accelerated, UI framework for Rust, designed to support a wide variety of applications.

- [website](https://www.gpui.rs)
- [crates.io](https://crates.io/crates/gpui)

## Apps

- [zed](https://github.com/zed-industries/zed): A high-performance, multiplayer code editor from the creators of Atom and Tree-sitter.
- [bmo](https://github.com/rubbieKelvin/bmo): Pomorodo timer written with rust & gpui.
- [coop](https://github.com/lumehq/coop): A simple, fast, and reliable nostr client for secure messaging across all platforms.
- [Fast Forward]]]></description>
            <pubDate>2025-12-07</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Solo Founders</title>
            <link>https://solofounders.com/report</link>
            <description><![CDATA[A REPORT FROM THE FRONTTHE STATE OF SOLO FOUNDINGToday, solo founding is considered odd. Soon it will be the default. This report features exclusive Carta data alongside commentary from solo founders who have raised over $250M and the investors who backed them.By submitting your information, you agree to the processing of your personal data by Carta as described in Carta's Privacy Policy and Terms of Service.For the first time in history, solo founders start over one-third of new companies.This milestone represents a 53% increase from 2019, when solo-founded companies accounted for less than o]]></description>
            <pubDate>2025-12-10</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>CSS Wrapped 2025</title>
            <link>https://chrome.dev/css-wrapped-2025/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[    # Invoker Commands Show a <dialog> modally (and more) without JavaScript!  Try the demo Chrome for Developers MDN    To open a <dialog> modally by clicking a <button> you typically need an onclick handler that calls the showModal method on that <dialog>. <button onclick="document.querySelector('#my-dialog').showModal();">Show Dialog</button>
<dialog id="my-dialog">…</dialog> With invoker commands–available from Chrome 135–buttons can now perform actions on other elements declaratively, without the need for any JavaScript. <button commandfor="my-dialog" command="show-modal">Show Dialog</but]]></description>
            <pubDate>2025-12-10</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Automerge</title>
            <link>https://automerge.org/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
    The team behind Automerge.
    For more than a decade, Automerge has been an independent open source project built by a serious, dedicated team of engineers and computer scientists. That team includes production engineers who cofounded Heroku, and computer scientists like renowned Cambridge professor Martin Kleppmann. We plan for the long-term, and think about where the project will be in a decade, not how to get through the next funding round.
    
    We are driven to build high performance, reliable software you can bet your project on. We develop rigorous academic proofs of our design]]></description>
            <pubDate>2025-12-11</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>