<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>linkstitcher/saveds</title>
        <link>https://github.com/rybla/linkstitcher</link>
        <description>The linkstitcher feed for saved URLs.</description>
        <image>
            <url>https://www.rybl.net/favicon.ico</url>
            <title>rybl/linkstitcher</title>
            <link>https://github.com/rybla/linkstitcher</link>
        </image>
        <item>
            <title>Can advanced AI lead to negative economic growth?</title>
            <link>https://open.substack.com/pub/aleximas/p/will-advanced-ai-lead-to-negative?r=2il09&amp;utm_medium=ios&amp;shareImageVariant=overlay</link>
            <description><![CDATA[This essay is about the role of economic demand in AI-driven growth forecasts. The premise is simple: if advanced AI (or AGI, which I will use interchangeably) automates most labor and the wage share collapses, who will buy the increased output? If firms anticipate weak demand, will they keep investing and producing? Will the economy face a gap between potential and realized output, and actually shrink?Let’s take a simple parable, suggested to me by Tom Cunningham, that illustrates this logic. Imagine there’s an island with 100 workers and 10 capital owners. Everyone consumes two types of good]]></description>
            <pubDate>2026-01-29</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>The golden age of vaccine development</title>
            <link>https://worksinprogress.co/issue/the-golden-age-of-vaccine-development/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[In 1796, when Edward Jenner developed the first vaccine, against the smallpox virus, no one knew what viruses were, let alone connected them to diseases. 



Many believed Jenner’s vaccine worked because it depleted the body of the specific nutrients the disease needed to thrive. In reality, his concept worked because of the good fortune that cowpox infections provided cross protection against smallpox. It would take almost a century to work out how to develop vaccines against other diseases.Get the print magazineSubscribe for $100 to receive six beautiful issues per year.Subscribe



Stocks o]]></description>
            <pubDate>2026-01-29</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>What’s Wrong with NIH Grants?</title>
            <link>https://www.statecraft.pub/p/whats-wrong-with-nih-grants</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Mike Lauer is the former Deputy Director for Extramural Research at the National Institutes of Health. A cardiologist and researcher, he joined the NIH’s National Heart, Lung, and Blood Institute in 2007 as the Director of the Division of Prevention and Population Science. From 2015, he oversaw the NIH’s $32 billion funding program for external research. Since leaving NIH in 2025, he has become an outspoken advocate for fundamental reform in how the federal government supports biomedical research.Why the NIH used to fund 60% of grant applications, and now funds just 10%How “soft money” forces]]></description>
            <pubDate>2026-01-29</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <link>https://www.ijcai.org/proceedings/2025/1238.pdf</link>
            <pubDate>2026-01-29</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Gloire Days - Liberties</title>
            <link>https://libertiesjournal.com/articles/gloiredays/?referrer=luma</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Though democracy is ostensibly the opposite of monarchy, the mass culture that is American democracy has betrayed in every age a deep atavistic yearning for royalty. From the days of “King” Andrew Jackson to those of the “Kingfish,” Huey Long; from the era of the Robber Barons to the age of the movie “kings” and “queens”; from the first black demagogues, Marcus Garvey and Father Divine, to the “Prophet,” Elijah Muhammed; from the earliest Mafia chieftains to the bowing, kneeling, and hand-kissing of The Godfather; from the regal F.D.R. to the “Imperial Presidency”]]></description>
            <pubDate>2026-01-29</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Lessons from a President: Why Obama Could Not Reform American Foreign Policy</title>
            <link>https://www.palladiummag.com/2018/12/20/lessons-from-a-president-why-obama-could-not-reform-american-foreign-policy/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Many presidential candidates have declared their intention to reform American foreign policy. The positive response of voters toward such rhetoric has contributed to the victories of two recent presidents: Barack Obama and Donald Trump. We may not have a clear understanding of the Trump administration’s national security decision-making process for years. His initial foreign policy, more orthodox than expected, has now given way to a “Cheneyism,” as reflected by his new band of hardline advisers. Whether he’s favoring more hardline instincts or has been “captured” by the Washington f]]></description>
            <pubDate>2026-01-29</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>A Deep Dive into the MiniMax-M2-her - MiniMax News</title>
            <link>https://www.minimax.io/news/a-deep-dive-into-the-minimax-m2-her-2</link>
            <description><![CDATA[ResearchProductAPINewsCompanyLog in2026.1.27Worlds to Dream, Stories to Live
｜How we built a Role-Play Agent for the production usageThree Years of Observations: How We Define Role-PlayThis year marks our third year optimizing Role-Play in Talkie / Xingye.Three years is long enough for a product to leave its mark on users' lives, and long enough for a user to form a deep bond with the NPC. Beyond the product metrics, we have found that the most valuable insights come from the user behaviors reflecting their real needs.Here are a few signals that are most interesting: The "Regenerate" button fo]]></description>
            <pubDate>2026-01-29</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <link>https://badrish.net/papers/bftree-vldb2024.pdf</link>
            <pubDate>2026-01-29</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Towards a Science of Scaling Agent Systems</title>
            <link>https://arxiv.org/pdf/2512.08296</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Source: ArXiv

Agents, language model-based systems that are capable of reasoning, planning, and acting are becoming the dominant paradigm for real-world AI applications. Despite this widespread adoption, the principles that determine their performance remain underexplored. We address this by deriving quantitative scaling principles for agent systems. We first formalize a definition for agentic evaluation and characterize scaling laws as the interplay between agent quantity, coordination structure, model capability, and task properties. We evaluate this across four benchmarks: Finance-Agent, BrowseComp-Plus, PlanCraft, and Workbench. With five canonical agent architectures (Single-Agent and four Multi-Agent Systems: Independent, Centralized, Decentralized, Hybrid), instantiated across three LLM families, we perform a controlled evaluation spanning 180 configurations. We derive a predictive model using coordination metrics, that achieves cross-validated R^2=0.524, enabling prediction on unseen task domains. We identify three effects: (1) a tool-coordination trade-off: under fixed computational budgets, tool-heavy tasks suffer disproportionately from multi-agent overhead. (2) a capability saturation: coordination yields diminishing or negative returns once single-agent baselines exceed ~45%. (3) topology-dependent error amplification: independent agents amplify errors 17.2x, while centralized coordination contains this to 4.4x. Centralized coordination improves performance by 80.8% on parallelizable tasks, while decentralized coordination excels on web navigation (+9.2% vs. +0.2%). Yet for sequential reasoning tasks, every multi-agent variants degraded performance by 39-70%. The framework predicts the optimal coordination strategy for 87% of held-out configurations. Out-of-sample validation on GPT-5.2, achieves MAE=0.071 and confirms four of five scaling principles generalize to unseen frontier models.]]></description>
            <pubDate>2026-01-29</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>