<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>linkstitcher/saveds</title>
        <link>https://github.com/rybla/linkstitcher</link>
        <description>The linkstitcher feed for saved URLs.</description>
        <image>
            <url>https://www.rybl.net/favicon.ico</url>
            <title>rybl/linkstitcher</title>
            <link>https://github.com/rybla/linkstitcher</link>
        </image>
        <item>
            <title>GPT-5.2 Review: Incredibly Impressive, But Too Slow</title>
            <link>https://shumer.dev/gpt52review</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
      I've had access to GPT-5.2 since November 25th, and after two weeks of putting it through its paces across coding, research, creative writing, and everyday tasks, I have a lot of thoughts. This review covers both the standard GPT-5.2 Thinking model as well as GPT-5.2 Pro; though I've also written a deeper Pro-specific review, because that model deserves its own dedicated post.

      The short version: GPT-5.2 is a meaningful step forward, particularly in how well it follows complex instructions and how willing it is to actually attempt difficult tasks. Pro mode improves on GPT-5.1 Pro ]]></description>
            <pubDate>2025-12-17</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Giving people money helped less than I thought it would</title>
            <link>https://open.substack.com/pub/theargument/p/giving-people-money-helped-less-than?r=2il09&amp;utm_medium=ios</link>
            <description><![CDATA[U.S. singer Eartha Kitt is seen at the end of the Poor People March, on June 19, 1968, in Washington, D.C. (Photo by ARNOLD SACHS/AFP via Getty Images)Just give people money. It's the simple, brute-force solution to so many problems. In low-income countries, charities are sometimes measured against whether their interventions are better than simply giving people cash. Even in high-income countries like the U.S., when disaster strikes, often the best thing you can do is get money into the hands of affected people immediately. They know whether they should use it to buy gas, rent an Airbnb or fl]]></description>
            <pubDate>2025-12-17</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Why AGI Will Not Happen — Tim Dettmers</title>
            <link>https://timdettmers.com/2025/12/10/why-agi-will-not-happen/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[If you are reading this, you probably have strong opinions about AGI, superintelligence, and the future of AI. Maybe you believe we are on the cusp of a transformative breakthrough. Maybe you are skeptical. This blog post is for those who want to think more carefully about these claims and examine them from a perspective that is often missing in the current discourse: the physical reality of computation. I have been thinking about this topic for a while now, and what prompted me to finally write this down was a combination of things: a Twitter thread, conversations with friends, and a growing ]]></description>
            <pubDate>2025-12-17</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <link>https://www.arxiv.org/pdf/2512.09762</link>
            <pubDate>2025-12-22</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Malleable software: Restoring user agency in a world of locked-down apps</title>
            <link>https://www.inkandswitch.com/essay/malleable-software/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[

Motivation
We want to adapt our environments
Environments matter. To do our best work and live our best lives, we need spaces that let us each express our unique potential.
A guitar maker sets up their workshop with their saws, hammers, chisels and files arranged just so. They can also build new tools as needed to achieve the best result—a wooden block as a support, or a pair of pliers sanded down into the right shape.



Over the years, a home cook gradually assembles a combination of knives, cutting boards, and pots and pans, finding the ones that work best for them. They can install hooks]]></description>
            <pubDate>2025-12-22</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>How Journalists Can Turn Speeches, Blog Posts, Books &amp; News Articles Into Illustrative Infographics Using Nano Banana Pro – The GDELT Project</title>
            <link>https://blog.gdeltproject.org/how-journalists-can-turn-speeches-blog-posts-books-news-articles-into-illustrative-infographics-using-nano-banana-pro/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
                                        Much of the conversation about AI and journalism centers on the potential conflicts between the two fields, while the reality is that there is much AI can offer the field of journalism to help journalists cover a world that is moving ever faster and in a distribution landscape that prioritizes visuals ever more. Given all of our success this week transforming a vast range of material into beautiful and easy-to-understand infographics using Nano Banana Pro, we got to thinking how journalists might be able to use these same approaches. Obviously our work]]></description>
            <pubDate>2025-12-22</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>