<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>linkstitcher/saveds</title>
        <link>https://github.com/rybla/linkstitcher</link>
        <description>The linkstitcher feed for saved URLs.</description>
        <image>
            <url>https://www.rybl.net/favicon.ico</url>
            <title>rybl/linkstitcher</title>
            <link>https://github.com/rybla/linkstitcher</link>
        </image>
        <item>
            <title>Metascience in Dangerous Times</title>
            <link>https://www.macroscience.org/p/metascience-in-dangerous-times</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Ship in a Storm on a Rocky Coast, by Jan Porcellis (painted around 1618). Source: Wikimedia. As Macroscience relaunches, a fundamental question has been on my mind. Namely, how must metascience adapt to understand the shape of science in the coming years?Since we went on hiatus late last year, the Trump administration has fundamentally reconfigured the government’s involvement in American science and research. The norms that govern the degree to which political authorities intervene in the life of the academy have been reshaped. From cuts to research funding to the reworking of overhead rules,]]></description>
            <pubDate>2025-12-07</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <link>https://github.com/zed-industries/awesome-gpui</link>
            <description><![CDATA[# awesome-gpui

A hybrid immediate and retained mode, GPU accelerated, UI framework for Rust, designed to support a wide variety of applications.

- [website](https://www.gpui.rs)
- [crates.io](https://crates.io/crates/gpui)

## Apps

- [zed](https://github.com/zed-industries/zed): A high-performance, multiplayer code editor from the creators of Atom and Tree-sitter.
- [bmo](https://github.com/rubbieKelvin/bmo): Pomorodo timer written with rust & gpui.
- [coop](https://github.com/lumehq/coop): A simple, fast, and reliable nostr client for secure messaging across all platforms.
- [Fast Forward]]]></description>
            <pubDate>2025-12-07</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Solo Founders</title>
            <link>https://solofounders.com/report</link>
            <description><![CDATA[A REPORT FROM THE FRONTTHE STATE OF SOLO FOUNDINGToday, solo founding is considered odd. Soon it will be the default. This report features exclusive Carta data alongside commentary from solo founders who have raised over $250M and the investors who backed them.By submitting your information, you agree to the processing of your personal data by Carta as described in Carta's Privacy Policy and Terms of Service.For the first time in history, solo founders start over one-third of new companies.This milestone represents a 53% increase from 2019, when solo-founded companies accounted for less than o]]></description>
            <pubDate>2025-12-10</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>CSS Wrapped 2025</title>
            <link>https://chrome.dev/css-wrapped-2025/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[    # Invoker Commands Show a <dialog> modally (and more) without JavaScript!  Try the demo Chrome for Developers MDN    To open a <dialog> modally by clicking a <button> you typically need an onclick handler that calls the showModal method on that <dialog>. <button onclick="document.querySelector('#my-dialog').showModal();">Show Dialog</button>
<dialog id="my-dialog">…</dialog> With invoker commands–available from Chrome 135–buttons can now perform actions on other elements declaratively, without the need for any JavaScript. <button commandfor="my-dialog" command="show-modal">Show Dialog</but]]></description>
            <pubDate>2025-12-10</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Automerge</title>
            <link>https://automerge.org/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
    The team behind Automerge.
    For more than a decade, Automerge has been an independent open source project built by a serious, dedicated team of engineers and computer scientists. That team includes production engineers who cofounded Heroku, and computer scientists like renowned Cambridge professor Martin Kleppmann. We plan for the long-term, and think about where the project will be in a decade, not how to get through the next funding round.
    
    We are driven to build high performance, reliable software you can bet your project on. We develop rigorous academic proofs of our design]]></description>
            <pubDate>2025-12-11</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>wen.works</title>
            <link>https://wen.works/2016/03/20/one-lambda-calculus-many-times/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[     One λ-calculus, many times… 
Written by
 
on
       Previously, I mentioned that one of the most common posts on Agda blogs is implementing the simply-typed λ-calculus. Gergő Érdi even goes as far as to call it the FizzBuzz of dependently-typed programming, and rightfully so: If you do a quick search, you’ll find dozens of examples.In Dependently-Typed Programming with Agda, Ulf Norell implements a type checker the simply-typed λ-calculus; Francesco Mazzoli more or less follows Ulf, but extends his λ-calculus with a primitive operator for addition; and, Gergő Érdi extends Ulf’s approach w]]></description>
            <pubDate>2025-12-12</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>