<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>linkstitcher/saveds</title>
        <link>https://github.com/rybla/linkstitcher</link>
        <description>The linkstitcher feed for saved URLs.</description>
        <image>
            <url>https://www.rybl.net/favicon.ico</url>
            <title>rybl/linkstitcher</title>
            <link>https://github.com/rybla/linkstitcher</link>
        </image>
        <item>
            <title>expMath: Exponentiating Mathematics | DARPA</title>
            <link>https://www.darpa.mil/research/programs/expmath-exponential-mathematics</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Mathematics is the source of significant technological advances. However, progress in math is slow for two primary reasons.Decomposing problems into useful lemmas is a laborious and manual process. To advance the field of mathematics, mathematicians use their knowledge and experience to explore candidate lemmas, which, when composed together, prove theorems. Ideally, these lemmas are generalizable beyond the specifics of the current problem so they can be easily understood and ported to new contexts.Proving candidate lemmas is slow, effortful, and iterative. Putative proofs may have gaps, such]]></description>
            <pubDate>2025-12-02</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=5680782</title>
            <link>https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=5680782</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Title: https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=5680782]]></description>
            <pubDate>2025-12-02</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=5770722</title>
            <link>https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=5770722</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Title: https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=5770722]]></description>
            <pubDate>2025-12-02</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Vercel Security Checkpoint</title>
            <link>https://venturebeat.com/ai/6-proven-lessons-from-the-ai-projects-that-broke-before-they-scaled</link>
            <description><![CDATA[ Vercel Security Checkpoint | iad1::1764662504-bLceYRfwLBPpdedZX3v7zt1JKEKqdRny ]]></description>
            <pubDate>2025-12-02</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Safe: Enhancing Mathematical Reasoning in Large Language Models via Retrospective Step-aware Formal Verification</title>
            <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.04592#:~:text=limiting%20their%20effectiveness,proving%20with%20%2430%2C809%24%20formal%20statements</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Source: ArXiv

Chain-of-Thought (CoT) prompting has become the de facto method to elicit reasoning capabilities from large language models (LLMs). However, to mitigate hallucinations in CoT that are notoriously difficult to detect, current methods such as process reward models (PRMs) or self-consistency operate as opaque boxes and do not provide checkable evidence for their judgments, possibly limiting their effectiveness. To address this issue, we draw inspiration from the idea that "the gold standard for supporting a mathematical claim is to provide a proof". We propose a retrospective, step-aware formal verification framework $Safe$. Rather than assigning arbitrary scores, we strive to articulate mathematical claims in formal mathematical language Lean 4 at each reasoning step and provide formal proofs to identify hallucinations. We evaluate our framework $Safe$ across multiple language models and various mathematical datasets, demonstrating a significant performance improvement while offering interpretable and verifiable evidence. We also propose $FormalStep$ as a benchmark for step correctness theorem proving with $30,809$ formal statements. To the best of our knowledge, our work represents the first endeavor to utilize formal mathematical language Lean 4 for verifying natural language content generated by LLMs, aligning with the reason why formal mathematical languages were created in the first place: to provide a robust foundation for hallucination-prone human-written proofs.]]></description>
            <pubDate>2025-12-02</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>My AI Skeptic Friends Are All Nuts</title>
            <link>https://fly.io/blog/youre-all-nuts/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
            
                
                
                  Image by
                  

  
    
  


                    
                      Annie Ruygt
                    
                
            
          A heartfelt provocation about AI-assisted programming.
Tech execs are mandating LLM adoption. That’s bad strategy. But I get where they’re coming from.

Some of the smartest people I know share a bone-deep belief that AI is a fad —  the next iteration of NFT mania. I’ve been reluctant to push back on them, because, well, they’re smarter than me. But their arguments are unse]]></description>
            <pubDate>2025-12-02</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>https://www.aei.org/op-eds/rapid-fertility-decline-is-an-existential-crisis/</title>
            <link>https://www.aei.org/op-eds/rapid-fertility-decline-is-an-existential-crisis/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Title: https://www.aei.org/op-eds/rapid-fertility-decline-is-an-existential-crisis/]]></description>
            <pubDate>2025-12-02</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Token embeddings violate the manifold hypothesis</title>
            <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2504.01002</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Source: ArXiv

A full understanding of the behavior of a large language model (LLM) requires our grasp of its input token space. If this space differs from our assumptions, our comprehension of and conclusions about the LLM will likely be flawed. We elucidate the structure of the token embeddings both empirically and theoretically. We present a novel statistical test assuming that the neighborhood around each token has a relatively flat and smooth structure as the null hypothesis. Failing to reject the null is uninformative, but rejecting it at a specific token $ψ$ implies an irregularity in the token subspace in a $ψ$-neighborhood, $B(ψ)$. The structure assumed in the null is a generalization of a manifold with boundary called a \emph{smooth fiber bundle} (which can be split into two spatial regimes -- small and large radius), so we denote our new hypothesis test as the ``fiber bundle hypothesis.'' By running our test over several open-source LLMs, each with unique token embeddings, we find that the null is frequently rejected, and so the evidence suggests that the token subspace is not a fiber bundle and hence also not a manifold. As a consequence of our findings, when an LLM is presented with two semantically equivalent prompts, if one prompt contains a token implicated by our test, the response to that prompt will likely exhibit less stability than the other.]]></description>
            <pubDate>2025-12-02</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Type Theory with Explicit Universe Polymorphism</title>
            <link>https://drops.dagstuhl.de/entities/document/10.4230/LIPIcs.TYPES.2022.13</link>
            <description><![CDATA[

                                

        Abstract

                    The aim of this paper is to refine and extend proposals by Sozeau and Tabareau and by Voevodsky for universe polymorphism in type theory. In those systems judgments can depend on explicit constraints between universe levels. We here present a system where we also have products indexed by universe levels and by constraints. Our theory has judgments for internal universe levels, built up from level variables by a successor operation and a binary supremum operation, and also judgments for equality of universe levels.
      ]]></description>
            <pubDate>2025-12-02</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <link>https://www.cl.cam.ac.uk/~jdy22/papers/normalization-by-evaluation-with-free-extensions.pdf</link>
            <pubDate>2025-12-02</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Lazy Linearity for a Core Functional Language</title>
            <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.10361</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Source: ArXiv

Traditionally, in linearly typed languages, consuming a linear resource is synonymous with its syntactic occurrence in the program. However, under the lens of non-strict evaluation, linearity can be further understood semantically, where a syntactic occurrence of a resource does not necessarily entail using that resource when the program is executed. While this distinction has been largely unexplored, it turns out to be inescapable in Haskell's optimising compiler, which heavily rewrites the source program in ways that break syntactic linearity but preserve the program's semantics. We introduce Linear Core, a novel system which accepts the lazy semantics of linearity statically and is suitable for lazy languages such as the Core intermediate language of the Glasgow Haskell Compiler. We prove that Linear Core is sound, guaranteeing linear resource usage, and that multiple optimising transformations preserve linearity in Linear Core while failing to do so in Core. We have implemented Linear Core as a compiler plugin to validate the system against linearity-heavy libraries, including linear-base.]]></description>
            <pubDate>2025-12-02</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>The Bloomer&apos;s Paradox</title>
            <link>https://www.astralcodexten.com/p/the-bloomers-paradox?utm_campaign=post&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;triedRedirect=true</link>
            <description><![CDATA[In Jason Pargin’s I’m Starting To Worry About This Black Box Of Doom, a manic pixie dream girl cajoles a shut-in incel loser to drive her and her mysterious box cross-country. The further they drive, the more evidence starts to build that she is a terrorist and her box is a nuke. As our protagonist becomes increasingly desperate to turn around and return to his comfortable world of social media feeds and psych meds, she pleads with him to come out of his shell, learn to trust people offline, and have a sense of adventure. The book’s dramatic tension comes from our simultaneously rooting for hi]]></description>
            <pubDate>2025-12-02</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>The Case That A.I. Is Thinking</title>
            <link>https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2025/11/10/the-case-that-ai-is-thinking</link>
            <description><![CDATA[ChatGPT does not have an inner life. Yet it seems to know what it’s talking about.November 3, 2025How convincing does the illusion of understanding have to be before you stop calling it an illusion?Animations by Zach LiebermanDario Amodei, the C.E.O. of the artificial-intelligence company Anthropic, has been predicting that an A.I. “smarter than a Nobel Prize winner” in such fields as biology, math, engineering, and writing might come online by 2027. He envisions millions of copies of a model whirring away, each conducting its own research: a “country of geniuses in a datacenter.” In June, Sam]]></description>
            <pubDate>2025-12-02</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Writing For The AIs</title>
            <link>https://www.astralcodexten.com/p/writing-for-the-ais</link>
            <description><![CDATA[American Scholar has an article about people who “write for AI”, including Tyler Cowen and Gwern. It’s good that this is getting more attention, because in theory it seems like one of the most influential things a writer could do. In practice, it leaves me feeling mostly muddled and occasionally creeped out.“Writing for AI” means different things to different people, but seems to center around:Helping AIs learn what you know.Presenting arguments for your beliefs, in the hopes that AIs come to believe them.Helping the AIs model you in enough detail to recreate / simulate you later.Going through]]></description>
            <pubDate>2025-12-02</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Remote Amazon tribe finally connects to  internet — only to wind up hooked on porn, social media</title>
            <link>https://nypost.com/2024/06/04/lifestyle/remote-amazon-tribe-connects-to-elon-musks-starlink-internet-service-become-hooked-on-porn-social-media/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
							


A reclusive tribe in the Amazon finally got hooked up to the internet, thanks to Elon Musk — only to be torn apart by social media and pornography addiction, elders complain.



Brazil’s 2,000-member Marubo tribe has been left bitterly divided by the arrival of the Tesla founder’s Starlink service nine months ago, which connected the remote rainforest community along the Ituí River to the web for the first time. 



“When it arrived, everyone was happy,” Tsainama Marubo, 73, told The New York Times. 



“But now, things have gotten worse. Young people have gotten lazy because of the]]></description>
            <pubDate>2025-12-02</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <link>https://x.com/lawrpaulson/status/1993300548758692332?s=12</link>
            <description><![CDATA[ Just out: Functional Data Structures, edited by Tobias Nipkow  pic.twitter.com/2Li133BDqd — Lawrence Paulson (@LawrPaulson)  November 25, 2025 
 

]]></description>
            <pubDate>2025-12-02</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <link>https://verse-lab.org/papers/veil-dafny26.pdf</link>
            <pubDate>2025-12-02</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <link>https://verse-lab.org/papers/velvet-dafny26.pdf</link>
            <pubDate>2025-12-02</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Teaching an LLM a Niche Diagraming Language</title>
            <link>https://www.huy.rocks/everyday/12-01-2025-ai-teaching-an-llm-a-niche-diagraming-language</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Text-to-diagram seems to be an area that has been solved perfectly by LLMs, but only with popular languages like Mermaid or PlantUML. There are many other less popular diagramming languages like D2, Structurizr, or Pintora. I want to see how far I can go teaching an LLM one of these languages, and Pintora◹ seems like a nice option to pick because I know there will not be a lot of LLMs trained with this language. At least, not the small ones.
Project goalSo, I set out the goal for this training project. It will be an LLM that has the ability to work with Pintora diagrams, for the following task]]></description>
            <pubDate>2025-12-05</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title></title>
            <link>https://muratkasimov.art/Ya/Tutorials/Command-line-task-manager-7/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[   /Я language (β)/Tutorials/Command line task manager 7/   Full source code ⋅ Previous chapter ⋅ Next chapter Let's introduce task statuses - they either completed or waiting for completion:   type Status = Unit `S` Unit   In addition we add pattern synonyms to avoid confusion:   pattern TODO e = This e     pattern DONE e = That e   Statuses should be included in a task type declaration:   type Task = Status `P` String   Printing expression is bloating, it's good time to split it on lines and blocks:   > line = is @( Cursor `P` Task )     >> `yio'yio'yoi` TODO `hu` "TODO" `la` DONE `hu` "DONE]]></description>
            <pubDate>2025-12-05</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Effect is Kleisli, etymologically</title>
            <link>https://luthenwald.github.io/blogs/effect-kleisli.html</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
      
      
      It's pretty intriguing that the Effect type in this blog is exactly the traditional Kleisli type in haskell. We'll further show that Monad is the constraint we need to form the valid Effect category. If you are wondering about the meaning of effects in the haskell world, I believe this blog will help gain some understanding.
      
import           Data.Kind ( Type )

import           Prelude   hiding ( Just, Maybe, Monad, Nothing, id, return, (<=<), (=<<), (>=>), (>>=) )


      The Effect Type
      When I was perplexitying about effects in haskell, the result was disapp]]></description>
            <pubDate>2025-12-05</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Google Summer of Code 2025 Wrap-up | The Haskell Programming Language&apos;s blog</title>
            <link>https://blog.haskell.org/gsoc-2025/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
    
      Google Summer of Code 2025 Wrap-up

      
          Aaron Allen  November 24, 2025  [Haskell.org] #Summer of Code  #Announcement  #GSoC 

    


The Haskell.org committee is pleased to present the results of Haskell's
participation in the Google Summer of Code 2025. This marks our 14th time
taking part in GSoC!



Of the four projects alloted to our organization, three were successfully
completed:

Implement Signature Help for Haskell Language Server
Qualified Imports and Alias Resolution in Liquid Haskell
Documenting and Improving CMM


Congratulations to all the contributors and]]></description>
            <pubDate>2025-12-05</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>https://www.stackbuilders.com/insights/hasktorch-libtorch-haskell-bindings-for-deep-learning-using-ffi/</title>
            <link>https://www.stackbuilders.com/insights/hasktorch-libtorch-haskell-bindings-for-deep-learning-using-ffi/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Title: https://www.stackbuilders.com/insights/hasktorch-libtorch-haskell-bindings-for-deep-learning-using-ffi/]]></description>
            <pubDate>2025-12-05</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>What if you don&apos;t need MCP at all?</title>
            <link>https://mariozechner.at/posts/2025-11-02-what-if-you-dont-need-mcp/</link>
            <description><![CDATA[



2025-11-02



One chonky MCP server






My Browser DevTools Use CasesProblems with Common Browser DevTools for Your AgentEmbracing Bash (and Code)The Start ToolThe Navigate ToolThe Evaluate JavaScript ToolThe Screenshot ToolThe BenefitsAdding the Pick ToolAdding the Cookies ToolA Contrived ExampleMaking This Reusable Across AgentsIn Conclusion


After months of agentic coding frenzy, Twitter is still ablaze with discussions about MCP servers. I previously did some very light benchmarking to see if Bash tools or MCP servers are better suited for a specific task. The TL;DR: both can be eff]]></description>
            <pubDate>2025-12-05</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Metascience in Dangerous Times</title>
            <link>https://www.macroscience.org/p/metascience-in-dangerous-times</link>
            <description><![CDATA[Ship in a Storm on a Rocky Coast, by Jan Porcellis (painted around 1618). Source: Wikimedia. As Macroscience relaunches, a fundamental question has been on my mind. Namely, how must metascience adapt to understand the shape of science in the coming years?Since we went on hiatus late last year, the Trump administration has fundamentally reconfigured the government’s involvement in American science and research. The norms that govern the degree to which political authorities intervene in the life of the academy have been reshaped. From cuts to research funding to the reworking of overhead rules,]]></description>
            <pubDate>2025-12-07</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <link>https://github.com/zed-industries/awesome-gpui</link>
            <description><![CDATA[# awesome-gpui

A hybrid immediate and retained mode, GPU accelerated, UI framework for Rust, designed to support a wide variety of applications.

- [website](https://www.gpui.rs)
- [crates.io](https://crates.io/crates/gpui)

## Apps

- [zed](https://github.com/zed-industries/zed): A high-performance, multiplayer code editor from the creators of Atom and Tree-sitter.
- [bmo](https://github.com/rubbieKelvin/bmo): Pomorodo timer written with rust & gpui.
- [coop](https://github.com/lumehq/coop): A simple, fast, and reliable nostr client for secure messaging across all platforms.
- [Fast Forward]]]></description>
            <pubDate>2025-12-07</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>